Mathias Verraes

mathias@verraes.net • Ghent, Belgium • Born 1979-07-02

Summary

I'm a Freelance Web Application Developer with 7 years of experience. I've worked in Document and Content Management Systems, E-commerce and, more recently, Credit Control software. I have a very high standard of quality, using agile methodologies, test driven development, code reviews, and refactoring. I enjoy mentoring junior team members.

Skills

Languages	PHP, Javascript
Frameworks	Symfony 1&2, Doctrine 1&2, Zend, AngularJs, jQuery, NodeJs
Databases	MySQL, Oracle 11g, Lucene, Redis, MongoDB
Development tools	Git/Github, Subversion, PHPStorm, Eclipse
Quality Assurance	PHPUnit, Behat, Jenkins, JIRA
Deployment tools	Puppet, Ant, Phing
Documentation	UML, Sphinx/ReST
Operating systems	Linux, OS X, Windows
Human languages	Dutch (native), English (fluent speaking and writing), French (basic)

Work Experience

Italian Institute of Technology - Genova, Italy - January 2012 - Present

Consulting and development for the document management system

iController - Ghent, Belgium - November 2011 - October 2012

Lead developer

- Built a new application for e-invoicing
- Brought a 400 kLoC legacy credit control application under tests
- Introduced Scrum, unit tests, continuous integration and code reviews in the team
- Assessed candidates, grew the team from 4 to 9 people

Marlon - Ghent, Belgium - April 2011 - October 2011

SMS-Parking 4411.be (Mobile-for / Belgacom)

- worked on the stability of the 250 kLoC code base
- built an integration with an existing credit control system
- built tools for a specialized security analysis
- performed ongoing maintenance and improved test coverage

E-commerce framework

- Designed and built a DDD architecture for e-commerce and stock management
- Led a team of four from start to deployment

Delius - Ghent, Belgium - July 2010 - March 2011

- Designed and built a centralized REST service for online fundraising applications
- Led a team of three in building clients applications for the framework
- Introduced TDD to the team

Timble - Diest, Belgium - July 2007 - June 2010

- Created the Nooku Framework for Joomla
- Built Nooku Content, an application for managing multilingual content
- Turned DOCman, an open source DMS, into a successful commercial application
- Consulted for clients such as the Belgian Police, and the British NHS

Freelance Consultant - September 2005 - July 2007

Built custom CMS solutions, based around Joomla, for various customers

Freelance music composer - 2002 - 2008

- Wrote music for short films and documentaries, TV commercials and pop albums
- Founded and conducted an a cappella pop choir

Education

Master in Music, Royal Conservatory - Ghent, Belgium - 1998-2003 I am an autodidact in the field of software development.

Community Engagement

I am an open source enthusiast and have contributed to many OSS projects. As a speaker, I have been invited to talk about technical topics at many Joomla conferences all over Western Europe. When time permits, I maintain a blog on software development.

Interests

I enjoy reading both fiction and non-fiction; when I'm not buried in a software book, I like to broaden my horizon with subjects like General Systems Thinking, and Evolutionary Biology.